Jim Webb

Programmer/Analyst

Tallmadge, OH - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Jim-Webb/a76257f565a503d9

Business Analyst and Programmer with demonstrated success working with management and users to provide and maintain data and automation systems necessary for smooth and accurate execution of daily and long-term business plans. Consistently provides comprehensive support for recurrent and ad hoc reporting to management and external customers. Self-motivated and focused individual, who pursues new opportunities to improve processes, stretch abilities, expand knowledge and bring maximum feasible returns to employer. Experiences include:

- Reporting System Design Hyperion VBA Programming
- Power Load Forecasting
 Power Price Forecasting
- Fuel Price Forecasting Emissions Price Forecasting
- Database Design/Maintenance

(MSAccess and Oracle)

- MSExcel Processes and Reports
- VBScript
- VB.NET and MSExcel VBA Automation (Data Capture and Transfer)
- XML
- Logistics Project Management
- Market Trading Contract Writing
- Contract Management
- Substation Design
- Production Cost Forecasting
- Electric Power System Protection
- Power Plant Operations

Willing to relocate to: Richmond, VA

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Programmer/Analyst (Contract)

Modis at FirstEnergy Corp. - Akron, OH - March 2017 to Present

(MSOffice VBA SME) Remote HelpDesk Projects Supporting an MSAccess Application and general MSOffice 2016 transition issues, using ServiceMaster.

Contract Employee

Robert Half at Summa - Akron, OH - May 2017 to May 2017

New Epic rollout at Summa Akron Locations

Programmer/Analyst (Contract)

Robert Half Technology at Danaher Corp. - Mayfield Heights, OH - December 2016 to March 2017

(Excel VBA SME)

Two projects: revising, improving automation and creating first-time documentation of a system using a Sharepoint supported portal and MSExcel for worldwide annual U.S. Tax Data Collection; moving data to ShrPt.

Analyst/Tester

TEKSYSTEMS at AMTrust Financial - Cleveland, OH - August 2016 to October 2016

AS400 CPS Replacement Project - Participated in Discovery Process.

- Organized Shared workspaces and led or participated in User Interviews.
- Did a breakdown of a massive Workflow structure.
- Automated a process for producing a tailored index of Business Functions from detailed descriptions in individual Worksheets of an Excel Workbook.

Programmer/Analyst (Contract)

ROBERT HALF TECHNOLOGY at Goodyear Tire & Rubber Co. - Akron, OH - 2014 to 2016

(Excel VBA SME)

Assisted in and then assumed full responsibility for implementation of new Sales and Operations Planning Reporting System modernizing an older system depending on linked and exchanged Excel Workbooks to a system using source Excel Workbooks, an Oracle Database, Web Portals, a VB.Net program, and Excel Objects for flexible reporting.

- Completed an initial design of a projection optimization system for the Holtz-Winter forecasting of manufacturing volumes and other metrics.
- Produced exhaustive evidence of inadequacies in the existing database structure.
- Assisted in the design of re-structured database tables.
- Completed adoption of new system to first Primary Business Units (at least six) at one level of reporting (potentially at least four). Demonstrated inflexibility of existing reporting structure.
- Designed, wrote and implemented a system of Excel Objects and VBA Code Modules that allowed application of the new system to all Primary Business Units at all levels of reporting.
- Documented the new system.
- Trained personnel assigned to long-term support of the process, and documented the training.

Programmer/Analyst (Contract)

ROBERT HALF TECHNOLOGY at Goodyear Tire & Rubber Co. - Akron, OH - 2013 to 2013

(Excel VBA SME)

Designed, developed or wrote large portions of a new Manufacturing Operations Reporting System to modernize a system previously entirely dependent upon linked and emailed Excel Workbooks by use of Excel Workbooks as source documents, a database for long-term data storage, and Excel Objects for flexible reporting.

- Persuaded the steering committee that their original concept would not be sufficiently responsive to User's
- Mocked-up an alternate design with the tools at hand.
- Provided input to the ultimate decision on a suitable database product.
- Helped to develop and write VBA code to assist in the transfer of data from source Workbooks to the Hyperion Database by use of Hyperion AddIn Functions.
- Assisted in the initial population of the database.
- Assisted in documentation of the new system

Business Analyst IV

FIRSTENERGY CORP - Akron, OH - 2010 to 2012

Designed, wrote or maintained all of the automated systems (comprised of dozens of databases, workbooks and programs) used by Load and Price Forecasting. Produced several Load and Price Forecasts, daily or weekly. More than doubled output with ~10% increase in staff.

- Managed systems through major merger more than doubling data requirements.
- Managed systems through transition from operation in one market (Midwest ISO) to another (PJM).

- Produced new quarterly Corporate Reporting Document with dozens of new charts and graphs.
- Assisted with corporate consolidation of data sources, having first collected many in separate databases, into a single corporate database.
- Maintained physically remote separate facility for emergency operations.

Sr. Business Analyst in Forecasting Analytics

FIRSTENERGY CORP - 2008 to 2010

Provided data for and produced period and ad hoc reports on market conditions for presentation to upper management.

- Designed new corporate databases and populated by gathering large quantities of publicly available or vendor provided industry-related data.
- Automated numerous periodic reports.
- Automated costing of an optional pricing structure offered by Marketing to selected customers.

Sr. Business Analyst

FIRSTENERGY CORP - 2005 to 2008

Helped write, maintain and expand automated systems to transfer data between databases and load forecasting / modeling software and provided related reports and performance tracking.

- Assumed responsibility for all automated systems.
- Provided savings of >\$200K by going to a seven day a week operation.
- Incorporated second parallel set of forecasting software into daily operations.
- Facilitated network consolidation / relocation of all Forecasting data.
- Trained new employee to take over all of my routine responsibilities.

Shift Foreman, Technologist, Engineer, Commodity Trader, Business Analyst

Work for FIRSTENERGY CORP Prior to 2005 - December 2005 to December 2005

Engineering, Operations (-2005)

Investigated opportunities to learn and contribute to diverse functions and segments of the company to learn as much as possible about the Electric Power Industry. Added consistency and efficiency through procedures, documentation and automation. Based on education and interest, became primary interface with IT in every position held after leaving Plant Operations.

- Operations team member working start-up of all three units at supercritical coal-fired power plant, culminating in a position as Shift Foreman. Laid the foundation for system of reporting and tracking trouble reports across various plant departments.
- Relay Protection Technologist, responsible for relay setting and fault calculations. Supported documentation and some of the first computer automation to the processes.
- Operational Planning Task Force team member, provided evaluation and implementation of new software for Production Costing. Given full responsibility for corporate Production Costing, automated related input formatting and data transfer functions. Developed corporation's first computerized system for handling Material Safety Data Sheets.
- Fuels Engineer, used modeling software to estimate true value of burning particular coals in specific unit, and to determine optimal inventory at generating plants.
- Emissions Trader, and then Coal Trader, developed and automated total process while increasing profit by \$1M.
- Sr. Business Analyst in Fuel Transportation, evaluated potential future rail options, producing analysis that lead to the corporation's first ownership and operation of rail cars. Automated numerous periodic reports, and developed corporations first system for classifying coals within a new mark-to-market / transaction entry / risk management system.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering

University of Akron - Akron, OH

Bachelor of Science in Mathematics / Physics

University of Pittsburgh - Pittsburgh, PA

SKILLS

Business Analysis (10+ years), Programming (10+ years)

CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES

Professional Engineer

December 2017

GROUPS

Cleveland Engineering Society

July 2015 to Present